<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="character_race_options">
        <item>Dwarf</item>
        <item>Elf</item>
        <item>Halfling</item>
        <item>Human</item>
        <item>Dragonborn</item>
        <item>Gnome</item>
        <item>Half-Elf</item>
        <item>Half-Orc</item>
        <item>Tiefling</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="race_dwarf_details"><![CDATA[
    These short and stocky defenders of mountain fortresses are often seen as stern and humorless; they\'re known for mining the earth\'s treasures and crafting magnificent items from ore and gemstones.
    ]]></string>
    <string name="race_elf_details"><![CDATA[
    Tall, noble, and often haughty, elves are long-lived and subtle masters of the wilderness, and excel in the arcane arts.
    ]]></string>
    <string name="race_halfling_details"><![CDATA[
    Members of this diminutive race find strength in family, community, and their own innate and seemingly inexhaustible luck.
    ]]></string>
    <string name="race_human_details"><![CDATA[
    Ambitious, sometimes heroic, and always confident, humans have an ability to work together toward common goals that makes them a force to be reckoned with.
    ]]></string>
    <string name="race_dragonborn_details"><![CDATA[
    Born to fight, dragonborn are a race of wandering mercenaries, soldiers, and adventurers.
    ]]></string>
    <string name="race_gnome_details"><![CDATA[
    Gnomes are whimsical artisans and tinkers, creating strange devices powered by magic, alchemy, and their quirky imagination; they have an insatiable need for new experiences that often gets them in trouble.
    ]]></string>
    <string name="race_half_elf_details"><![CDATA[
    Often caught between the worlds of their progenitor races, half-elves are a race of both grace and contradiction.
    ]]></string>
    <string name="race_half_orc_details"><![CDATA[
    Often fierce and savage, sometimes noble and resolute, half-orcs can manifest the best and worst qualities of their parent races.
    ]]></string>
    <string name="race_tiefling_details"><![CDATA[
    Tieflings, often descendants of fiends and humans, are known for their cunning, allure, and leadership.</string>
    ]]></string>
</resources>